If students are placed in the academic English preparation program
AEP（アカデミック英語準備プログラム）からスタートした場合、
the amount of time these students will spend in AEP varies.
このプログラムに在籍する期間は、生徒それぞれ異なります。
Students placed in level one will complete the AEP program in four, five or six terms.
一般的に、レベル1（ビギナー）から始めた生徒はAEPを4～6学期で終了します。
Students placed in level two will complete the AEP program in three, four or five terms.
レベル２から始めた生徒のAEP在籍期間は3～5学期、
In Level three, they will complete the AEP program in two, three or four terms.
レベル3から始めた生徒のAEP在籍期間は2～4学期ほどです。
And in level four they will complete the program in one or two terms
レベル４から始めた生徒は、1～2学期でAEPプログラムを終了します。
Students who arrive with very weak English will take longer,
英語力がまだ低い生徒は、AEP終了に時間がかかります。
Students who study hard speak English a lot
英語をなるべくたくさん話し、英語の本を読み、
and read English books will progress faster.
努力を続ける生徒は、勿論、英語力が早くつきます。
Students who participate extracurricular programs
課外プログラムに参加したり、
and interact with students from other countries will progress faster
他の国からの生徒と交流を持つことでも、上達が早くなります。
All students arrive at Bodwell with different English experiences
ボドウェルの生徒の英語経験は様々です。
some students have learned a little English before arriving
入学前に少し英語を勉強してきた生徒もいますし
but have never practiced it.
あまり勉強をしたことのない生徒もいます。
Some students have studied English for many years in their home countries
さらに自国で長年英語を勉強してきた生徒や
or have studied English in other countries other before arriving at Bodwell.
ボドウェル入学前に他の国で
Some students have completed high school courses
英語を学んできた生徒、
at a Canadian public school.
カナダの公立高校からの転校生もいます。
It's very important for students that wish to progress through the AEP program
AEPで上のレベルに、
and get ready
進級し、できるだけ、
for the regular academic program as quickly as possible
早くアカデミックプログラムに進級しようと努力することがとても大切です。
that they get involved and they use English
また、教室の外で、様々なことに参加して、
as much as they can outside of the classroom.
英語を使うことも大切です。
There's many opportunities
土曜日のプログラムや
such as our Saturday enrichment program
チューターがついての自習時間、クラブ、
our study Hall sessions with our tutors, our clubs,
チーム、寮でのアクティビティ、
teams, boarding activities,
ボランティアの機会の他、
volunteer opportunities
日常生活でも、生徒が他の国からの
and daily life where they speak
留学生と話をしたり、ともに学ぶ
and learn with other students from other different countries
機会が、ボドウェルには沢山あります。
all of these things help students progress through the AEP program
上記のすべての事は、AEPプログラムへの進級を助け、
and get ready, have those essential skills
良い成績を修める為に、必要なスキルを
needed for academic success.
取得するのに、とても役立ちます。
Older students age 17, with weak English
英語取得の速さは、ひとそれぞれです。17歳以上で
struggle to complete the AEP program
英語が苦手な生徒は、年齢が若い生徒より、
and the regular academic program
人一倍頑張り、AEPだけでなく、アカデミックプログラムを、
before they reach the age of 18  or 19
18や19歳になるまでに終了させる必要があります。
Younger students must learn English,
一方で、年齢が低い生徒は英語だけでなく、
life skills and become mature all at the same time.
ライフスキルや、人間的・精神的な成長も必要になります。
Young students progress at different rates.
また、年齢が低い生徒の英語力上達の速さにも、個人差があります。